<?xml version="1.0"?>
<definitions xmlns="http://www.elasticpath.com/schema/rest/0.5">

	<family>
		<name>navigations</name>
		<description>
			<![CDATA[
####Entry Point: /navigations/{scope}

Navigation nodes organize your store's catalogs by providing containers to group related items into. Each navigation node
can contain details (attributes), any number of [items][items], and other child nodes. Your company's marketers create these navigation nodes, also known as categories, using the Commerce Manager. You may need
to coordinate with your marketers for how the navigation nodes should be used in your client application.

[items]: #items
]]></description>

		<uri-part>
			<name>node-id</name>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[The navigation ID. Navigation nodes can have other child nodes.
				The node-id is a list of all ids denoting the path from the root node.
				For the root node, the navigation id is a list containing one element.]]>
			</description>
			<string/>
		</uri-part>

		<resource>
			<name>navigations</name>
			<description><![CDATA[All the top level navigation nodes for a store.]]></description>
			<uri>{base.family}/{base.scope}</uri>
			<list-of>navigation</list-of>
		</resource>

		<resource>
			<name>navigation</name>
			<description><![CDATA[A single navigation node.]]></description>
			<uri>{navigations}/{node-id}</uri>
			<entity>navigation</entity>
		</resource>

		<relationship>
			<name>navigations-from-root</name>
			<description><![CDATA[Navigations can be found from the root resource.]]></description>
			<rel>navigations</rel>
			<from>base.root</from>
			<to>navigations</to>
		</relationship>

		<relationship>
			<name>navigation-to-top</name>
			<description><![CDATA[The navigation to the top navigations resource.]]></description>
			<rel>top</rel>
			<from>navigation</from>
			<to>navigations</to>
		</relationship>

		<relationship>
			<name>parent-node-to-child</name>
			<description><![CDATA[Navigate from a parent to a child navigation.]]></description>
			<rel>child</rel>
			<rev>parent</rev>
			<from>navigation</from>
			<to>navigation</to>
		</relationship>

		<entity>
			<name>navigation</name>
			<description><![CDATA[A single navigation node.]]></description>
			<property>
				<name>name</name>
				<description><![CDATA[The Cortex system's name for the node.]]></description>
				<string/>
			</property>
			<property>
				<name>display-name</name>
				<description><![CDATA[The localized name of the node, intended for display in the client application.]]></description>
				<string/>
			</property>
			<property>
				<name>node-id</name>
				<description><![CDATA[The internal node identifier.]]></description>
				<internal/>
				<string/>
			</property>
			<property>
				<name>details</name>
				<description>
					<![CDATA[
An array of the navigation node's attributes. Attributes describe the details of the navigation node, like the node's name,
description, associated subcategories, etc. Attributes are different each store. To get a list of navigation attributes, you'll need to coordinate with your store marketer who creates these navigation nodes and attributes.
					]]>
				</description>
				<array>
					<is-a>base.details</is-a>
				</array>
			</property>
			<entity-type>elasticpath.navigations.node</entity-type>
		</entity>

	</family>
</definitions>
